[
    {
        "question": "Which of the following command is used to count the total number of lines, words, and characters contained in a file?",
        "answer": "Answer -  A) wc is used to count the total number of lines, words, and characters contained in a file.",
        "options": [
            "wc",
            "wcount",
            "countw",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the command which is used to remove files.",
        "answer": "Answer -  b) rm is used to remove files.",
        "options": [
            "delete",
            "rm",
            "dm",
            "erase"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the hardware structure which is not supported by Red Hat?",
        "answer": "Answer -  d) Macintosh is not supported by Red Hat.",
        "options": [
            "IBM-compatible",
            "Alpha",
            "SPARC",
            "Macintosh"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following command which is used with vi editors to delete a single character?",
        "answer": "Answer -  B) x is used with vi editors to delete a single character.",
        "options": [
            "a",
            "x",
            "y",
            "z"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the TCP/IP Protocol which is used for remote terminal connection service?",
        "answer": "Answer -  D) TELNET is used for remote terminal connection service.",
        "options": [
            "FTP",
            "UDP",
            "RARP",
            "TELNET"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the service which is used to translate a domain name to IP address.",
        "answer": "Answer -  B) DNS is used to translate a domain name to IP address.",
        "options": [
            "NIS",
            "DNS",
            "SMB",
            "NFS"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following command is used to add a new user to the system?",
        "answer": "Answer -  D) All of the above is used to add a new is a to the system",
        "options": [
            "Using Linuxconf",
            "Using adduser",
            "Using useradd",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total primary partitions that can exist on one drive is_____________",
        "answer": "Answer -  D) A total of 4 primary partitions that can exist on one drive.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "16",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "FSF stands for __________",
        "answer": "Answer -  C) FSF stands for Free software Foundation.",
        "options": [
            "File server first",
            "Free software file",
            "Free software Foundation",
            "First server first"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the command which is used to remove files.",
        "answer": "Answer -  C) rmdir is used to remove files.",
        "options": [
            "rd",
            "remove",
            "rmdir",
            "rdir"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the command which is used to create Linux File systems.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) mkfs is used to create Linux File systems.",
        "options": [
            "fsck",
            "mkfs",
            "fdisk",
            "mount"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the one which is not a communication command",
        "answer": "Answer - C) grep is not a communication command.",
        "options": [
            "mail",
            "mesg",
            "grep",
            "write"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to back up over typing errors in vi?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) # is used to backup over typing errors in vi.",
        "options": [
            "$",
            "#",
            "@",
            "!"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the command used to add printing jobs to the queue.",
        "answer": "Answer - D) lpr is used to add printing jobs to the queue",
        "options": [
            "lpd",
            "lpq",
            "lpc",
            "lpr"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the server which is used with the BIND package?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) named is used with the BIND package.",
        "options": [
            "shttp",
            "dns",
            "named",
            "httpd"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "By default, which port does squid listen to?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) Squid listens by default port 3128",
        "options": [
            "4322",
            "3128",
            "7334",
            "2314"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following commands is used to display the octal value of the text?",
        "answer": "Answer - A) od command is used to display the octal value of the text.",
        "options": [
            "od",
            "oct",
            "octal",
            "text_oct"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "GNU stands for ___________.",
        "answer": "Answer - C) GNU stands for GNU’s not Unix.",
        "options": [
            "Greek Needed Unix",
            "General Unix",
            "GNU’s Not Unix",
            "General Noble Unix"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the core of the Linux operating system?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) The core of the Linux operating system is a kernel",
        "options": [
            "Terminal",
            "Kernel",
            "Command",
            "Terminal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following directory does the configuration files are present?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) /etc/ contains the configuration files in Linux.",
        "options": [
            "/bin/",
            "/root/",
            "/etc/",
            "/dev/"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "Identify the OS which is not based on Linux.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) BSD is not based on Linux.",
        "options": [
            "Ubuntu",
            "BSD",
            "CentOS",
            "Red Hat"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the command which is used to record sessions in Linux",
        "answer": "Answer - C) Both a and b are used to record session in Linux.",
        "options": [
            "script",
            "session",
            "Both a and b",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the user password stored?",
        "answer": "Answer - A) User password is stored in /etc/passwd.",
        "options": [
            "/etc/passwd",
            "/root/password",
            "/etc/password",
            "/root/passwd"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the default file system type of Linux",
        "answer": "Answer - A) ext3 is the default file system type of Linux.",
        "options": [
            "ext3",
            "ext2",
            "ext",
            "mimix"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which command is used to display the operating system name",
        "answer": "Answer - B) uname is used to display the operating system name.",
        "options": [
            "wc",
            "uname",
            "countw",
            "os"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which command is used to print a file",
        "answer": "Answer - C) lp command is used to print a file.",
        "options": [
            "wc",
            "pg",
            "lp",
            "print"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which option of ls command used to view file inode number",
        "answer": "Answer - B) -i command used to view file inode number.",
        "options": [
            "-l",
            "-i",
            "-o",
            "-a"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Using which of the following command can hidden files be viewed?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) ls -a is used to view hidden files.",
        "options": [
            "ls -h",
            "ls -a",
            "ls -l",
            "ls -k"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following sign is used to represent the user home directory?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) ~ is used to represent the user home directory",
        "options": [
            "/",
            ".",
            "~",
            ".."
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the command which is used to set terminal IO characteristics.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) stty is used to set terminal IO characteristics.",
        "options": [
            "ctty",
            "stty",
            "tty",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the command which is used to display the unix version.",
        "answer": "Answer - B) uname -r is used to display the UNIX version.",
        "options": [
            "uname -t",
            "uname -r",
            "uname -n",
            "kernel"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to represent the top-level directory?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) / .is used to represent the top-level directory.",
        "options": [
            "*",
            "$",
            "#",
            "/"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The dialogue control and token management are responsible for?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) The dialogue control and token management are responsible for Network layer.",
        "options": [
            "Session layers",
            "Datalink layer",
            "Transport layer",
            "Network layer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The main Apache configuration file is?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) /etc/httpd/conf/httpd.conf is the main Apache configuration file.",
        "options": [
            "/etc/httpd/config.ini",
            "/etc/apache.conf",
            "/etc/httpd/conf/httpd.conf",
            "/etc/srm.conf"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following command is used to see the services running in the NFS server?",
        "answer": "Answer - A) serverinfo is used to see the services running in NFS server.",
        "options": [
            "serverinfo",
            "rpcinfo",
            "infserv",
            "NFSinfo"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following command is used to sort the lines of data in a file in alphabetical order?",
        "answer": "Answer - C) sort is used to sort the lines of data in a file in alphabetical order.",
        "options": [
            "sh",
            "sort -r",
            "sort",
            "st"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Routing is performed by which of the following layers",
        "answer": "Answer - D) Routing is performed by session layer.",
        "options": [
            "Transport layer",
            "data link layer",
            "network layer",
            "session layer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of installations requires a special boot disk?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) All of the above require a special boot disk.",
        "options": [
            "FTP",
            "NFS",
            "PCMCIA",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "RPM ________",
        "answer": "Answer - C) RMP stands for Red Hat Package Manager.",
        "options": [
            "assigns a dynamic IP address",
            "is used to keep track of the users",
            "stands for Red Hat Package Manager",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify this script which is run for setting a global defaults for users",
        "answer": "Answer - D) /etc/profile is run for setting global defaults for users.",
        "options": [
            "/etc/.log",
            "/etc/.bashrc",
            "/etc/.profile",
            "/etc/profile"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Linux Kernel was founded by?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) Linus Torvalds founded Linux kernel",
        "options": [
            "Richard Stallman",
            "Linus Torvalds",
            "Bill Gates",
            "Ben Thomas"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following command can force all buffers to disk?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) sync can force all buffers to disk.",
        "options": [
            "save",
            "flush",
            "edbuff",
            "sync"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "To create a swap partition by using fdisk, which partition’s system ID type should be used?",
        "answer": "Answer - B) Partition’s system ID type 82 must be used.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "82",
            "5",
            "83"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following command is used to change the working directory?",
        "answer": "Answer - D) cd command is used to change the working directory.",
        "options": [
            "changed",
            "chdr",
            "dr",
            "cd"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "LILO stands for _____________-",
        "answer": "Answer - B) LILO stands for Linux loader.",
        "options": [
            "Linux Leveraging Order",
            "Linux loader",
            "Linux Low Order",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "NIS",
        "answer": "Answer - C) NIS is Network Information Service.",
        "options": [
            "is a simple directory service whose main purpose is to allow remote authentication of systems on local network systems",
            "allows configuration-such as password and group files",
            "is Network Information Service",
            "was formerly known as yellow page"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "OSS stands for _____________",
        "answer": "Answer - D) OSS stands for Open Source Software.",
        "options": [
            "Original Source Software",
            "Open System Software",
            "Original System Server",
            "Open Source Software"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following commands is used to display and create files?",
        "answer": "Answer - A) cat is used to display and create files.",
        "options": [
            "cat",
            "lyrix",
            "vi",
            "ed"
        ]
    }
]